Zach Schneider

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Cary, NC, 27511

Phone

(419) 376-0273

E-mail

zachary.schneider85@gmail.com

www

https://zschneid85.github.io/devportfolio/

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/zach-schneider-5151aa128

Skills

JavaScript	
	Very Good
Java	
	Excellent
Git	
	Good
HTML/CSS	
	Excellent
SQL	EXCONOTT
	Excellent
WordPress	LACGIIGI II
	Eveellent
PHP	Excellent
lOuan,	Very Good
JQuery	
De alaba a 5	Very Good
Bootstrap 5	
	Very Good

PROFILE Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

Work History

2018-08 -Current

Software Developer

Zip Code Solutions, Cary, NC

- Developing ,optimizing and maintaining websites and applications utilizing PHP, MySQL, Javascript , and various APIs to meet established goals of 30 plus clients.
- Creating Administrative backend so that clients can quickly update data by using databases.
- Migrating existing websites/applications to stable, high-maintainable platforms.
- Analyzing requirements and designing, developing and implementing software applications for multiple websites.
- Preparing and presenting technical proposals to clients focusing on needs.

2019-11 -2020-04

Lead Teacher

Wize Computing Academy, Exton, PA

- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional platforms Scratch, Lego wedo 2.0.
- Keeping 15 students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Chose optimum curriculum for each class and devised creative daily lesson plans to meet requirements and needs of different learners

2016-11 -2018-03

Medicaid Billing Rep

Conifer Health Solutions, Exton, PA

- Worked on 1,200 accounts per week with great attention to detail.
- Used wide range of Medicaid billing tools to resolve wide range of insurance denials.
- Produced \$150,000.00 per month in company revenue.

Education

2004-08 -

2018-03 - Certification of Completion: Software Development
2018-05 Rutgers University - New Brunswick

Coding Bootcamp

Bachelor of Science: History

2008-05 Eastern Michigan University - Ypsilanti, MI